Biggie & Tupac is a music, documentary film directed by Nick Broomfield.
In 1997, rap superstars Tupac Shakur and Christopher Wallace (aka Biggie Smalls, The Notorious B.I.G.) were
gunned down in separate incidents, the apparent victims of hip hop's infamous east-west rivalry.
Nick Broomfield's film introduces Russell Poole, an ex-cop with damning evidence that suggests the LAPD deliberately fumbled the case to
conceal connections between the police, LA gangs and Death Row Records, the label run by feared rap mogul Marion "Suge" Knight.
himself, played by Tupac Shakur.
himself, played by Nick Broomfield.
Himself (archive footage), played by The Notorious B.I.G..
Himself, played by Russell Poole.
Self - Biggie's Mother, played by Voletta Wallace.
Self - Tupac's Biological Father, played by Billy Garland.
Biggie & Tupac is a 2002 feature-length documentary film by Nick Broomfield
about the murdered American rappers the Notorious B.I.G.
and Tupac Shakur.
Broomfield suggests the two murders were planned by
Suge Knight, head of Death Row Records.
Collusion by the Los Angeles Police Department (LAPD) is also implied.
While the film remains inconclusive, when asked "Who killed Tupac?" in a BBC Radio interview dated March
7, 2005, Broomfield stated (quoting Snoop Dogg) "The big guy next to him in the car...
Suge Knight."